<quest title="Mistress Malaise" data-line="0">
  <roleplay icon="magic" title="A Holy Order" data-line="4">
    <p>Your party is a group of crusaders of the Order of Retribution, a holy order tasked with eliminating the undead presence that has recently grown across the land. An order has come from your superiors of a mission in the distant town of Brustwick, but your purpose there is unknown.</p>
    <p>Your contact for this mission is Brother Pell, a confidant and long-time friend who lives in Brustwick and knows much about goings-on in the town and the surrounding area.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay icon="adventurer" title="Arrival" data-line="10">
    <p>After several days' journey, you make it to the outskirts of the town just as the sun begins to set.</p>
    <p>As you walk towards Pell's house, you look around you; the run-down and dilapidated buildings loom imposingly, a fine mist rises from the ground, and a musty, moldy odor permeates the place.</p>
    <p>You find Pell's home and knock at the door, anxious to get inside.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay title="Brother Pell" data-line="18">
    <p>The door creaks open, and Brother Pell ushers your group in.</p>
    <p>Pell is... not what you expected. The joyous face you remember feasting, training, and fighting with in the Order has been replaced by a haggard, sickly one with sallow, sunken eyes.</p>
    <p>You ask in alarm what's been happening to the town; he invites you to sit, and begins a haunting story.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay icon="undead" title="The Mistress" data-line="26">
    <p>Pell tells the story of Mistress Malaise, an influential aristocrat who until recently had been vying for governance of the town. Despite her credentials, she was not a member of the governor's family and didn't stand a chance at inheriting the position. Decade after decade of rejection brewed a bitter hate for the ruling family, as well as an unquenchable ambition.</p>
    <p>After one final attempt, she vanished. Many assumed her dead - and over time the governor and his family began to grow ill, as did the entire town. When they died, Malaise emerged into prominence once more with the last will of the governor, stating that she was to rule.</p>
    <p>Ever since then, the town has grown more blighted, townsfolk have fallen ill, decayed bands of the undead are spotted on the town outskirts, and Malaise herself has aged backwards in time, becoming hauntingly beautiful.</p>
    <p>The evidence is clear: Malaise has become an immortal lich.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay icon="d20" title="The Job" data-line="36">
    <p>After days of spying on Malaise, Pell believes he has found her phylactery - the magical vessel in which she stored her soul when she became undead.</p>
    <p>The phylactery must be kept close to the lich and the spell renewed frequently, and Pell has seen her take frequent trips to the mausoleum of the governor. The place is shrouded in wards, trap spells, and magical locks that can only be designed to keep everyone away from something very valuable.</p>
    <p>If your party can travel to the mausoleum and find the phylactery, Pell can perform the unbinding ritual to release the soul from its container and make Malaise capable of being slain.</p>
    <p>You begin the hunt immediately.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay icon="bandit" title="Outside the Tomb" data-line="48">
    <p>The moist soil squishes underfoot as you enter the graveyard - the musty smell is much stronger here.</p>
    <p>It doesn't take long to spot the mausoleum. At the center of the graveyard rises a large and stately stone structure, very new-looking compared to the other headstones.</p>
    <p>Lurking near the entrance to the mausoleum, you find three stealthy-looking figures. They appear to be gathering up the courage to venture inside.</p>
    <p>What do you do?</p>
    <choice text="Call out to them.">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="60">
        <p>You shout out to them, announcing your presence. They appear startled and disappear inside.</p>
        <p>Not too long after, the screams begin.</p>
        <p>As you make it to the door, you hear a small explosion, a sickening crunching sound, and then silence. The Order doesn't pay you nearly enough for this.</p>
      </roleplay>
      <roleplay icon="undead" title="Inside the Tomb" data-line="66">
        <p>You take a last deep breath of the damp air outside and venture within.</p>
        <p>As you go deeper, you find each of the three bandits in turn, victim to the magical traps and wards set up by Malaise. You try not to think of the state the bodies are in, but make careful note of how they died and safely navigate the dangers of the outer rooms.</p>
        <p>Towards the end of a long corridor, you find one last door into the mausoleum's innermost chamber. You hear a creaking sound as you press against the door - but the noise didn't come from the door...</p>
      </roleplay>
    </choice>
    <choice text="Attempt to incapacitate them.">
      <roleplay icon="bandit" title="Subterfuge" data-line="76">
        <p>Your party quickly takes cover behind some nearby headstones and sneaks towards the group.</p>
        <instruction>
          <p>One of your party must roll a die at this time. Choose a next action based on the result of that roll:</p>
        </instruction>
        <choice text="Rolled above 10">
          <roleplay title="Hit and Run" data-line="84">
            <p>You sneak up on the shady figures and take them out silently.</p>
            <p>After a quick check you can confirm they're still breathing. Searching their pockets, you find a piece of parchment listing what appears to be the locations of various traps within. Paper in hand, you proceed into the tomb.</p>
          </roleplay>
        </choice>
        <choice text="Rolled 10 or below">
          <roleplay title="Bad Timing" data-line="92">
            <p>The shady figures sense your presence and draw their weapons.</p>
          </roleplay>
          <combat data-line="96">
            <e>Archer</e>
            <e>Rogue</e>
            <e>Brigand</e>
            <event on="win">
              <roleplay title="" data-line="104">
                <p>Searching the slain, you find a piece of parchment listing what appears to be the locations of various traps within. Paper in hand, you proceed into the tomb.</p>
              </roleplay>
            </event>
            <event on="lose">
              <roleplay title="" data-line="108">
                <p>As the world fades to black, your last thought is of the dishonor you've brought the Order.</p>
              </roleplay>
              <trigger data-line="110">end</trigger>
            </event>
          </combat>
        </choice>
      </roleplay>
      <roleplay title="Danger Dodged" data-line="112">
        <p>It's immediately clear that you wouldn't have stood a chance without foreknowledge of the traps within. Dodging spring traps, rusty spikes, and magical flames, you make your way to the innermost chamber.</p>
        <p>You hear a creaking sound as you press against the door - but the noise didn't come from the door...</p>
      </roleplay>
    </choice>
  </roleplay>
  <combat icon="undead" data-line="120">
    <e>Zombie</e>
    <e>Skeleton Mage</e>
    <event on="win">
      <roleplay icon="loot" title="Taking Stock" data-line="127">
        <p>The undead fiends lay slain at your feet - and resting on a podium in the center of the room is what could only be the phylactery mentioned by Brother Pell.</p>
      </roleplay>
    </event>
    <event on="lose">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="133">
        <p>The undead fiends let out an unearthly shriek of victory as the last of your party falls.</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="135">end</trigger>
    </event>
  </combat>
  <roleplay icon="loot" title="The Phylactery" data-line="137">
    <p>You take the phylactery from the pedestal and search the rest of the room, finding some additional supplies.</p>
    <instruction>
      <p>Draw two random tier I loot.</p>
    </instruction>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay icon="adventurer" title="The Party Emerges" data-line="143">
    <p>You emerge from the tomb, taking a moment to breathe the (mostly) fresh air. What you mistook for a headstone begins to move, shocking you out of complacency.</p>
    <p>The moving headstone is actually an old, feeble woman, who was apparently waiting for you to emerge. She calls herself Malaise, and begs for you to listen.</p>
    <choice text="Listen to her story">
      <roleplay icon="adventurer" title="Malaise Unmasked" data-line="151">
        <p>Malaise begins to tell a rather different story from Pell's - that the sickness began after her departure, but that the surge in undead activity is the fault of an old resident of Brustwick. A man skilled in binding rituals.</p>
        <p>A man by the name of Pell.</p>
        <p>With a wistful smile, she opens the box you looted from the mausoleum and reveals an empty glass bottle. Pell must have warded the grave and planted the false phylactery as a trap for adventurers to distract them from his real identity.</p>
        <p>Dejected and betrayed, you ask her where Pell hid his phylactery. She mentions that she doesn't know for sure, but it should be somewhere close to him if the lore is true.</p>
        <p>Then she stops, eyes wide in shock, as a sword emerges from her chest.</p>
      </roleplay>
      <combat icon="undead" data-line="163">
        <e>Wight</e>
        <e>Zombie Hand</e>
        <e>Zombie</e>
        <event on="win">
          <roleplay icon="d20" title="Change of Plans" data-line="171">
            <p>Wiping the viscera from your weapons, you stop to catch your breath. Malaise is dead, but the lich Pell still lives.</p>
            <p>It appears that your plans have changed.</p>
          </roleplay>
        </event>
        <event on="lose">
          <roleplay icon="undead" title="Boned" data-line="179">
            <p>Your party is no match for the onslaught of undead. You quickly succumb.</p>
          </roleplay>
          <trigger data-line="183">end</trigger>
        </event>
      </combat>
    </choice>
    <choice text="Attack her before she can speak">
      <roleplay title="Death of Malaise" data-line="187">
        <p>You leap at her before she has the chance to speak, slaying the old woman with a single blow.</p>
        <p>You step back in surprise. A lich should not have been slain so easily...</p>
        <p>You open the box that Brother Pell had asked you to retrieve. Instead of a phylactery, it contains an empty glass bottle. It was a trap!</p>
        <p>Brother Pell's misdirection can only mean one thing: That he is the lich.</p>
      </roleplay>
    </choice>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay icon="d20" title="Change of Plans" data-line="199">
    <p>As you make your way back to Pell's home, you think hard on what to do next.</p>
    <p>Your only hope is that Pell has hidden the real phylactery somewhere within his house - but you don't know exactly where.</p>
    <p>You entertain the thought of kicking down the door and incapacitating him with surprise on your side, but you don't know how a slain lich reacts with an intact phylactery.</p>
    <p>{{ (_.numAdventurers() &gt; 1) ? "On the other hand, you could send some of your party to sneak into the house. Meanwhile, the others could distract Pell at the entrance by asking for a place to recover, claiming that the rest of the party was \"slain\" after a failed assault on the Mausoleum. If any part of the bluff fails, you may not have your full party to fight with." : "On the other hand, you could sneak into the house and try to search for his phylactery. You may lose the element of surprise if you're discovered, though..." }}</p>
    <choice text="Take the direct approach.">
      <trigger data-line="211">goto planA</trigger>
    </choice>
    <choice text="Split your party to look for the phylactery." if=" _.numAdventurers() &gt; 1 ">
      <trigger data-line="215">goto planB</trigger>
    </choice>
    <choice text="Sneak in and search for the phylactery." if=" _.numAdventurers() &lt; 2 ">
      <trigger data-line="219">goto planB1P</trigger>
    </choice>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay icon="damage" title="The Direct Approach" id="planA" data-line="221">
    <p>You march up to the entrance of Pell's house, kick down the door, and enter with weapons drawn.</p>
    <p>Pell stands up from his dining table, sees your intent, and with a word summons a small band of undead minions.</p>
    <p>Any doubts you had are gone. Enraged at his betrayal, you attack.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <combat icon="undead" data-line="229">
    <e>Lich</e>
    <e>Zombie</e>
    <e>Skeleton Swordsman</e>
    <event on="win">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="237">
        <p>Broken and bleeding, Pell utters a final dark curse. You feel your reactions slow and you barely miss grasping the lich as he runs upstairs. He emerges again with phylactery in hand, leaps through his window, and escapes into the night.</p>
        <p>You curse your luck. Brustwick has been freed from the undead menace for now... but you expect it won't be long before Pell continues his necromancy somewhere else.</p>
        <p>For now, though, your work is done. You return to the Order, hoping to one day bring revenge upon Pell.</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="243">end</trigger>
    </event>
    <event on="lose">
      <trigger data-line="247">goto pelldefeat</trigger>
    </event>
  </combat>
  <roleplay icon="undead" title="A Cunning Plan" id="planB1P" data-line="249">
    <p>You manage to find a slightly cracked window in the upper rear of the house; it doesn't take long to climb into what you determine to be Pell's bedroom.</p>
    <p>You begin your search immediately.</p>
    <p>Spotting a loose board in the wall, you pry it away to reveal a box covered in carved runes and glowing ominously. You take it out and attempt to pry it open, but it doesn't budge. Out of ideas, you try a swift knock with your weapon.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay icon="undead" title="Discovered!" data-line="257">
    <p>With a shrill, bell-like sound, a crack appears on the box.</p>
    <p>You hear a crash and a howl of pain from downstairs, and multiple footsteps coming up swiftly from below.</p>
    <p>Before you get a chance to hide, the bedroom door explodes off its hinges. A furious Pell - and accompanying minions - emerges to meet you.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <trigger data-line="265">goto planBcombat</trigger>
  <roleplay icon="undead" title="A Cunning Plan" id="planB" data-line="267">
    <p>You split your party; one group knocks at the front door, and the other climbs in through an upper rear window.</p>
    <p>Brother Pell sees your haggard group and immediately adopts a look of sorrow as he notices those missing. You spin a tale of misfortune and triggered traps, as the other group searches Pell's bedroom for the phylactery.</p>
    <p>One of your party spots a loose board in the wall and pries it away, revealing a box covered in carved runes and glowing ominously. You take it out and attempt to pry it open, but it doesn't budge. Out of ideas, you try a swift knock with your weapon. With a shrill, bell-like sound, a crack appears on the box.</p>
    <p>Pell hears the sound and physically flinches as the blow hits. His eyes widen as he realizes your bluff - he leaps back and summons a group of undead.</p>
    <p>You rise to meet him.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay title="The Phylactery" data-line="279">
    <instruction>
      <p>Choose up to two players. Those players are the phylactery group.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>The phylactery group must only attack the phylactery until it's destroyed. When it is, they may join combat.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>The phylactery group does not take round damage, but is still affected by surges.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>Players not in the phylactery group may not attack the phylactery.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>At this time, draw a tier III Undead encounter and place it face-down with full health. This is the phylactery.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>Combat is ended when all enemies and the phylactery are destroyed.</p>
    </instruction>
  </roleplay>
  <combat icon="undead" id="planBcombat" data-line="293">
    <e>Lich</e>
    <e>Zombie</e>
    <e>Skeleton Swordsman</e>
    <event on="win">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="301">
        <p>As Pell gives his last, dying gasp, the phylactery shatters under a final blow. A shockwave from the box knocks {{ (_.numAdventurers() &gt; 1) ? "your party" : "you" }} to the ground, unconscious.</p>
        <p>When you manage to open your eyes once more, light peeks through the windows of Pell's house. You emerge to see a beautiful, natural sunrise. No mysterious fog or moldy smells remain.</p>
        <p>The townsfolk of Brustwick begin to emerge from their homes - they see the change, learn of Pell, and a celebration soon erupts.</p>
        <p>You participate in the festivities for a while, then begin the long trek back home. You can't wait to tell the Order about your victory!</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="309">end</trigger>
    </event>
    <event on="lose">
      <roleplay id="pelldefeat" title="Defeated" data-line="313">
        <p>Pell has defeated you - he quickly reanimates your bodies, to become new fodder for the next adventurer looking to slay the Lich of Brustwick.</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="317">end</trigger>
    </event>
  </combat>
</quest>
