<quest title="Learning 3: The Future" data-line="0">
  <roleplay title="Introduction" data-line="2">
    <p>Your adventure continues with <b>Expedition: The Future</b>.</p>
    <instruction>
      <p>When setting up, try to choose one of the adventurers from The Future.</p>
    </instruction>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay title="continue" data-line="8">
    <p>New in <b>The Future</b>: Skills</p>
    <instruction>
      <p>:skill: "Skills" are a new card type that help you succeed in mid-story skill checks, unlocking new paths. They can also be discarded during combat to activate a powerful, one-time boost.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>:skill: Skills have different core types (Knowledge, Athletics, Charisma). When prompted to make a skill check of the type listed on your card, add your current skill level to your roll.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>:skill: When you level up, you may now choose to learn (draw 3, keep 1) or level up a skill (by sliding your level up one marker, which may or may not increase the number) instead of drawing a new Ability.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>:skill: Skill levels persist across fights unless you choose to discard the skill for its single-use effect.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>:cards: For the purposes of this tutorial, each Adventurer should now draw three Skills, choose one, and return the others to the Skill deck.  Place your chosen Skill face-up next to your Adventurer and place a clip on its first level.</p>
    </instruction>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay title="continue" data-line="22">
    <p>After defeating the strange, terrible Hound and fleeing back to the guardhouse, you'd discovered the hastily scrawled note with the message:</p>
    <p>"I'm sorry - Peter."</p>
    <p>A pounding on the door makes you think you're still being pursued, and you flee to the back of the guardhouse. Desperate for a spot to hide, you open the first door you see - and are confronted with a large, silvery machine.</p>
    <p>The door opening causes it to whir to life, clanking loudly and shooting sparks everywhere.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay title="continue" data-line="32">
    <p>The doorway rends apart into some sort of rift... Through it, you see the pinprick points of starlight. The warmth and air are sucked from the room with explosive force.</p>
    <p>Before you can catch breath or turn to flee, you've been wrenched from your feet and pulled into the rift!</p>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay title="continue" data-line="37">
    <p>The sensation of floating weightless might otherwise be pleasant, were there any air to draw into your desperately heaving lungs. A blinding light steals your vision, as a gel-like substance encapsulates your head...</p>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay title="continue" data-line="40">
    <p>You wake up in a room with perfectly smooth, gray walls and no windows. A strange metal hexagon seems stuck to the back of your left hand. Lights pulse and play across its surface and you somehow "know" you've been selected as a specimen in an experiment. Other knowledge you never learned is also present in your mind...</p>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay title="continue" data-line="43">
    <p>New in "The Future": Tech Abilities.</p>
    <instruction>
      <p>:tech: Tech abilities are a powerful way to gain and use Loot to help friends and harm foes. Adventurers with at least one Tech ability may learn new tech abilities when leveling up.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>:cards: Any Adventurer that did not start with a Tech ability may draw one now.</p>
    </instruction>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay title="continue" data-line="51">
    <p>The metal door to the cell silently retracts into the ceiling, leaving a darkened corridor before you.</p>
    <p>"Survive!" a robotic voice blares inside your skull, causing you to wince.</p>
    <p>Choose the skill emphasis your strange hosts have imposed on your "neural architecture":</p>
    <instruction>
      <p>It is recommended adventurers have skills of different types (Knowledge, Athletics, Charisma). You need not all choose the same type, but the party can choose only one option below.</p>
    </instruction>
    <choice text="We've been given &quot;science&quot;, with an emphasis on &quot;Knowledge&quot; Skills.">
      <trigger data-line="63">goto Knowledge</trigger>
    </choice>
    <choice text="Social intuition has been infused into us. Our emphasis is on &quot;Charisma&quot; skills.">
      <trigger data-line="67">goto Charisma</trigger>
    </choice>
    <choice text="Our bodies were enhanced. Our emphasis is on &quot;Athletics&quot; skills.">
      <trigger data-line="71">goto Athletics</trigger>
    </choice>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay id="Knowledge" title="Blind Them with Science" data-line="73">
    <instruction>
      <p>All adventurers with a Knowledge skill may advance it one level forward.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>Adventurers without a Knowledge skill may draw one Loot from "The Future".</p>
    </instruction>
  </roleplay>
  <trigger data-line="79">goto Incursion</trigger>
  <roleplay id="Charisma" title="Dazzle Them with Wit" data-line="81">
    <instruction>
      <p>All adventurers with a Charisma skill may advance it one level forward.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>Adventurers without a Charisma skill may draw one Loot from "The Future".</p>
    </instruction>
  </roleplay>
  <trigger data-line="87">goto Incursion</trigger>
  <roleplay id="Athletics" title="Go in Hot" data-line="89">
    <instruction>
      <p>All adventurers with an Athletics skill may advance it one level forward.</p>
    </instruction>
    <instruction>
      <p>Adventurers without a Athletics skill may draw one Loot from "The Future".</p>
    </instruction>
  </roleplay>
  <trigger data-line="95">goto Incursion</trigger>
  <roleplay id="Incursion" title="Incursion" data-line="97">
    <p>A high-pitched hum greets your ears, seeming to come from everywhere at once.</p>
    <p>A metallic form hurtles into the room, reflecting the room's cold, hard lights. It is following closely by a swarm of tiny... things.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <combat data-line="103">
    <e>Nanoswarm</e>
    <e>Repulsor Probe</e>
    <event on="win">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="110">
        <p>You pause to catch your breath, and notice that the walls around you are still flawlessly smooth despite the battle. How many experiments have occurred in this room?</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="112">goto Next</trigger>
    </event>
    <event on="lose">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="116">
        <p>You're a failed experiment, though your body will surely be repurposed by the synths for some new purpose.</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="118">end</trigger>
    </event>
  </combat>
  <roleplay id="Next" title="Phase Two" data-line="120">
    <p>Past the shattered synth remnants is another door with a small control terminal.</p>
    <instruction>
      <p>Pick one of the below skill checks and have one Adventurer roll for it. If you succeed, select it. If you fail, select the final choice.</p>
    </instruction>
    <choice text="Hack the door terminal. Make a Knowledge :roll: of 9 or higher. Remember to add the rating number in your &quot;Knowledge&quot; skill to your :roll:!">
      <trigger data-line="127">goto KnowledgeT</trigger>
    </choice>
    <choice text="Brute force the door open. Make an Athletics :roll: of 15 or higher. Remember to add the rating number in your &quot;Athletics&quot; skill to your :roll:!">
      <trigger data-line="131">goto Brute</trigger>
    </choice>
    <choice text="Talk the door into opening. Make a Charisma :roll: of 12 or higher. Remember to add the rating number in your &quot;Charisma&quot; skill to your :roll:!">
      <trigger data-line="135">goto Charm</trigger>
    </choice>
    <choice text="Failed any of the above skill rolls.">
      <trigger data-line="139">goto Failure</trigger>
    </choice>
  </roleplay>
  <roleplay id="KnowledgeT" title="Hackjob" data-line="141">
    <p>A satisfying chime sounds from the terminal you've hacked and the door opens.  You enter into a large domelike structure. Above you, a turret swivels towards you and a red dot appears on your chest.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <combat data-line="144">
    <e>Sentry Turret</e>
    <event on="win">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="149">
        <p>You pause for a moment to observe the room, and notice that the dome is made of a transparent material. Beyond it, you can only see space. Where are you?</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="151">goto LearningA</trigger>
    </event>
    <event on="lose">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="155">
        <p>You're a failed experiment, though your body will surely be repurposed by the synths for some new purpose.</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="157">end</trigger>
    </event>
  </combat>
  <roleplay id="Failure" title="Failure" data-line="159">
    <p>A sharp electric jolt arcs from the door and throws you onto your back.</p>
    <instruction>
      <p>Take 3 points of damage.</p>
    </instruction>
    <p>The door opens, revealing the room beyond it. Recovering, you enter into a large dome-like structure. Above you, a turret of some sort swivels and draws a bead on you.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <combat data-line="166">
    <e>Sentry Turret</e>
    <event on="win">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="171">
        <p>You pause for a moment to observe the room, and notice that the dome is made of a transparent material. Beyond it, you can only see space. Where are you?</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="173">goto LearningA</trigger>
    </event>
    <event on="lose">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="177">
        <p>You're a failed experiment, though your body will surely be repurposed by the synths for some new purpose.</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="179">end</trigger>
    </event>
  </combat>
  <roleplay id="Brute" title="Power" data-line="181">
    <p>You strain with your newfound might against the metal, and find it yields before you do.  The door open, you enter into a large domelike structure. Above you, a turret of some sort swivels and draws a bead on you.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <combat data-line="184">
    <e>Sentry Turret</e>
    <event on="win">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="189">
        <p>You pause for a moment to observe the room, and notice that the dome is made of a transparent material. Beyond it, you can only see space. Where are you?</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="191">goto LearningA</trigger>
    </event>
    <event on="lose">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="195">
        <p>You're a failed experiment, though your body will surely be repurposed by the synths for some new purpose.</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="197">end</trigger>
    </event>
  </combat>
  <roleplay id="Charm" title="Charm" data-line="199">
    <p>You whistle a jaunty little tune and a chime issues in response from the door as it slides open.  You enter into a large domelike structure. Above you, a turret of some sort swivels and a red dot appears on your chest.</p>
  </roleplay>
  <combat data-line="202">
    <e>Sentry Turret</e>
    <event on="win">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="207">
        <p>You pause for a moment to observe the room, and notice that the dome is made of a transparent material. Beyond it, you can only see space. Where are you?</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="209">goto LearningA</trigger>
    </event>
    <event on="lose">
      <roleplay title="" data-line="213">
        <p>You're a failed experiment, though your body will surely be repurposed by the synths for some new purpose.</p>
      </roleplay>
      <trigger data-line="215">end</trigger>
    </event>
  </combat>
  <roleplay id="LearningA" title="TBC" data-line="217">
    <p>Moments after it's destruction, the Sentry Turret's chassis explodes in a ball of plasma. A rift like the one that brought you to this strange place coalesces in the fire and you feel the familiar, vortex-like pull as it sucks you in...</p>
    <p>Your adventure will continue in the next expansion!</p>
  </roleplay>
  <trigger data-line="223">end</trigger>
</quest>
